Guide to the Yevgeny Yevtushenko Papers M1088
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Manuscripts, Series 3.
  - Subseries 1. Poetry
    - Kitaiskii perevodchiki, undated (Box 12, Folder 13)
      Handwritten drafts, 12 p., n.d.
    - Krasnoe i chernoe, undated (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Krutoi Kipiatok, undated (Box 12, Folder 15)
      Handwritten draft, 1 p.
    - Listvennichnyi dvoinik, undated (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Liubov'-ditia planety, undated (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Loskutnoe odeialo, 1993 (Box 12, Folder 18)
      Handwritten drafts, 4 p., ca. 1993.
    - Mama, undated (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - Mama i neitronnaia bomba, undated (Box 12, Folder 20)
      Handwritten drafts and annotated typescripts, n.d.
    - Mama i neitronnaia bomba: Author's adaptation, 1983 Jan. (Box 12, Folder 21)
      Bound typescript, ca. 58 p., 1983 Jan.
    - Marsh Pobeditelei, undated (Box 12, Folder 22)
      Typescript, 2 p., n.d.
    - Medlennaia liubov', undated (Box 12, Folder 23)
    - Mertvaia Ruka, undated (Box 12, Folder 24)
    - Mezhdu stydom i strakhom, 1995 Jan. 3 (Box 12, Folder 25)
      TMsS, 1 p., 1995 Jan 3.
    - Mikhailu Shemiakinu, 1987 May 8 (Box 12, Folder 26)
      Copy of typescript, 1 p., 1987 May 8. Copy of handwritten draft, 1 p.
      Shemiakin, Mikhail
    - Moi universitety, undated (Box 12, Folder 27)
      Typescript and handwritten drafts, n.d.
    - Mysl' geniia, undated (Box 12, Folder 28)
      Annotated typescripts and handwritten drafts, n.d.
    - My - starye russkie, undated (Box 12, Folder 29)
    - My - zalozhniki, undated (Box 12, Folder 30)
    - Nad mogiloi pervogo maia, undated (Box 12, Folder 31)
      Handwritten and typescript draft, 2 p., n.d.
    - Nad Moskvoi, undated (Box 12, Folder 32)
    - Nado by poskunee, undated (Box 12, Folder 33)
      Handwritten drafts, 4 p., n.d.
    - Narod vyrastaet vo lbu..., undated (Box 12, Folder 34)
      Typescript and handwritten drafts, 4 p., n.d.
    - Nasha Pena, undated (Box 12, Folder 35)
    - Nasha Svoboda, 1995 July 6 - 1995 July 7 (Box 12, Folder 36)
      Handwritten drafts, 3 p., 1995 Jul 6-7 [?].
    - Nasledniki Stalina, 1962 Oct. 21 (Box 12, Folder 37)
      Handwritten drafts, 2 p., 1962 Oct 21.
    - Na smert' Chichibabina, 1994 Dec. 18 (Box 12, Folder 38)
      Handwritten drafts, 2 p., 1994 Dec 18.
      Chichibabin, Boris
    - Na smert' Dima Kholodova, 1994 Nov. 28 (Box 12, Folder 39)
      Handwritten drafts and copies of handwritten drafts, 1994 Nov. 28.
      Kholodova, D.
    - Na smert' Dzhon Lennona, undated (Box 12, Folder 40)
      Lennon, John
    - Na smert' Dzhumbera, 1989 (Box 12, Folder 41)
      Handwritten drafts, 7 p., ca. 1989 [?].
      Betashvili, Dzhumber
    - Na smert' Levi Ganskogo, undated (Box 12, Folder 42)
    - Na smert' Vladimira Sokolova, 1997 Jan. (Box 13, Folder 1)
      Handwritten drafts, 5 p.; typescripts, 8 p., 1997 Jan 25; clipping from Literaturnaia Gazeta, 1 p., 1997Jan 29.
      Sokolov, Vladimir
    - Ne Yeltsin vyigral, a Stalin proigral, 1996 (Box 13, Folder 2)
      Typescript and handwritten drafts, 17 p.
    - Neperesekaemyi platok, undated (Box 13, Folder 3)
      Typescript and handwritten drafts.
    - Ne poniatnym poetam, undated (Box 13, Folder 4)
      Handwritten drafts, 4 p.
    - Ne prospi, undated (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Ne razliubil ia ni odnoi liubimoi..., undated (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Neron, undated (Box 13, Folder 7)
      Annotated typescript, 1 p.
    - Net let, undated (Box 13, Folder 8)
      Handwritten drafts, 10 p.
    - Neverie v sebia neobkhodimo, undated (Box 13, Folder 9)
      Handwritten drafts, 2 p.
    - Nevsesil'nost', undated (Box 13, Folder 10)
      Handwritten drafts.
    - N'iu Iorkskii taksi, undated (Box 13, Folder 11)
      Handwritten drafts, 8 p.
    - Novye Russkie, undated (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Novyi god v Prage, undated (Box 13, Folder 13)
      Handwritten draft, 1 p. Typescript, 1 p.
    - Odessa, undated (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Okhota na medvedia, 1996 July 1 (Box 13, Folder 15)
      Handwritten drafts, 10 p. Typescripts, 3 p., 1996 July 1.
    - Opozdanie, undated (Box 13, Folder 16)
      Handwritten drafts, 11 p.
    - Ostrov sokrovishcha, undated (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - Otkrytoe pis'mo general'nomu prokuroru SSSR, undated (Box 13, Folder 18)
      Handwritten drafts, 20 p.
    - Otvet na "Otvet", 1961 (Box 13, Folder 18.5)
      To Aleksei Markov, 1 p., typescript with handwritten note by Epel'fel'd signed 1995 Mar. 26.
      Epel'fel'd,; Markov, Aleksei
    - Pamiati Eteri Kogonil, undated (Box 13, Folder 19)
      Handwritten drafts, 12 p.
    - Parodisty postanovlenii, undated (Box 13, Folder 20)
      Handwritten drafts, 14 p. Typescript, 1 p.
    - Paskhal'noe, undated (Box 13, Folder 21)
    - Pavlodar, undated (Box 13, Folder 22)
    - Perestroishchiki perestroiki, undated (Box 13, Folder 23)
      Handwritten drafts, 2 p.; typescript, 1 p.
    - Pervyi derevenshchik, undated (Box 13, Folder 24)
      Handwritten drafts, 16 p.
    - Pesnia Chippolino, undated (Box 13, Folder 25)
      Typescript, 2 p.
    - Pesnia Mastino, undated (Box 13, Folder 26)
    - Pesnia Nele, undated (Box 13, Folder 27)
    - Pesnia pro skazki Italii, undated (Box 13, Folder 28)
    - Pesnia Sin'ora - Pomidora, undated (Box 13, Folder 29)
    - Pesnia Sleptsov, undated (Box 13, Folder 30)
    - Pesnia Zhiliny, undated (Box 13, Folder 31)
      Typescript, 5 p.
    - Pik Pozora, undated (Box 13, Folder 32)
    - Pis'mo afgantsi, undated (Box 13, Folder 33)
      Handwritten and typescript drafts.
    - Pis'mo generalissim..., undated (Box 13, Folder 34)
    - Pit' v den' pobedi, undated (Box 13, Folder 35)
      Handwritten drafts, 6 p.
    - Pochti potselui, 1996 July 1 (Box 13, Folder 36)
      Handwritten drafts, 9 p., n.d.; typescript, 3 p., 1996 July 1.
    - Podavliushchie bol'shinstva, undated (Box 13, Folder 37)
      Handwritten drafts, 3 p.
    - Podpisanty, undated (Box 13, Folder 38)
    - Pokhoroni Okudzhavi, 1997 (Box 13, Folder 39)
      Handwritten drafts, 18 p., ca. 1997.
      Okudzhava, Bulat
    - Poslednaia popytka byt' schastlivym, undated (Box 14, Folder 1)
      Handwritten drafts and copies of handwritten drafts, 6 p.
    - Poteria, undated (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Pozdenie slezy [also called "Slezy starosti"], 1994 Aug. 25 (Box 14, Folder 3)
      Handwritten drafts, 5 p., n.d. Typescript (Slezy starosti), 1 p., 1994 Aug 25.
    - Pozharnik v kizhakh, undated (Box 14, Folder 4)
      Handwritten drafts and annotated typescripts.
    - Predutro [Pre-morning], undated (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Predzaveshchanie, undated (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Prelestnyi son, undated (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Printsessa, undated (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Prodazha dali, undated (Box 14, Folder 9)
      Handwritten and typescript drafts, 1 p.
    - Proizvoditeli urodstva, undated (Box 14, Folder 10)
      Handwritten drafts, 15 p. Placard, n.d.
    - Prokhindei, undated (Box 14, Folder 11)
      Heavily annotated typescript, 1 p.
    - Pro malen'kuiu Valen'ku, undated (Box 14, Folder 12)
      Hand color illustrated, unpublished bound booklet, 11 p.
    - Proshchai, nash krasnii flag, undated (Box 14, Folder 13)
      Handwritten drafts, 16.
    - Pushkin v Kvinse, undated (Box 14, Folder 14)
      Handwritten drafts, 15.
    - Razgovor, 1950 (Box 14, Folder 15)
      Typescript, 1 p., 1950?.
    - Razmyshleniia u chernogo khoda, undated (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - Razve eto prokhodit?, 1977 (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - Resnitsy, undated (Box 14, Folder 18)
    - Romen Gari, undated (Box 14, Folder 19)
    - Rossiia - babushka, undated (Box 14, Folder 20)
      Handwritten drafts, 14 p.
    - Rus' - Matushka, 1996 June 10 (Box 14, Folder 21)
      Typescript, signed, 1 p.
    - Russkie Koaly, undated (Box 14, Folder 22)
    - Samo upalo iabloko, 1995 Aug. 28 (Box 14, Folder 23)
      Handwritten drafts, 7 p., 1995 Aug. 28.
    - Samozhalost', undated (Box 14, Folder 24)
    - Satana, undated (Box 14, Folder 25)
      "Russkaia Muza XX Veka"; excerpts from Sluchevskii, Blok, and a chastushka; typescript, 3 p.
    - Semisvechnik, undated (Box 14, Folder 26)
      Handwritten drafts, n.d. Two copies of printed sheet with poem in Russian (Latin script), English, and Hebrew.
    - Serebrianyi bor, undated (Box 14, Folder 27)
      Annotated typescript, 3 p.
    - Shestidesiatniki, undated (Box 14, Folder 28)
      Handwritten drafts, 1 p.
    - Sokrovischcha, undated (Box 14, Folder 29)
      Handwritten drafts, 18 p
    - Soplivyi Fashizm, 1962 July 29 (Box 14, Folder 30)
      Typescript, 1 p., 1962 July 29.
    - Sorok deviatyi god, undated (Box 14, Folder 31)
    - Sred' v'iug moscovskikh, undated (Box 14, Folder 32)
    - Stalingradskie valsiki [?], undated (Box 14, Folder 33)
    - Stary drug, undated (Box 14, Folder 34)
    - Strakh glasnosti, undated (Box 14, Folder 35)
      Handwritten drafts, 6 p., n.d.; copy of signed typescript, 1 p.
    - Svatovstvo, undated (Box 15, Folder 1)
      Handwritten drafts, 5 p.
    - Tak dal'she zhit' nel'zia, undated (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Takoe chuvstvo, gospodi, undated (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Terpenie Rossii, undated (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Trassovochki, undated (Box 15, Folder 5)
      Handwritten drafts, 9 p.
    - Tretii Razvod, undated (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Tropa filosofov (Philosophenweg), undated (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Tsitsinately, undated (Box 15, Folder 8)
      Handwritten drafts, 17 p., n.d. Typescript, 2 p.
    - Tsvety dlia babushki, undated (Box 15, Folder 9)
      Handwritten drafts, n.d.; typescripts, 4 p.
    - Tvoi Sledy, undated (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - U sten Malopegi, undated (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Val's na polube, undated (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - V Amerikanskom Gospitale, 1996 July 16 (Box 15, Folder 13)
      Handwritten drafts, 7 p., n.d; annotated typescript, 1 p., 1996 July 16
    - Vandeia, undated (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Vavilenskaia bashnia, undated (Box 15, Folder 15)
      Handwritten drafts, signed, 2 p.
    - Vdova Bukharina, undated (Box 15, Folder 16)
      Handwritten drafts and typescripts.
    - Vechernaia Raduga, undated (Box 15, Folder 17)
      Handwritten drafts, some in English.
    - Velosipedy, undated (Box 15, Folder 18)
    - V gorode dozhd', undated (Box 15, Folder 19)
    - Vnutr' pozhara, undated (Box 15, Folder 20)
    - Vos'miletie poet, undated (Box 15, Folder 21)
      Handwritten drafts and typescript.
    - V pustyne Negiv, undated (Box 15, Folder 22)
    - Vse monety gliadiat vyzhid..., undated (Box 15, Folder 23)
    - Vspomnisia Charli Chaplina, undated (Box 15, Folder 24)
    - Vtoroe rozhdenie, undated (Box 15, Folder 25)
    - Vy krestites', undated (Box 15, Folder 26)
      Handwritten drafts, 17 p.
    - Zabastovka serdtsa: Pamiati A.D. Sakharova, undated (Box 15, Folder 27)
    - Zabytaia shtol'nia (Forgotten mine), undated (Box 15, Folder 28)
      Typescripts and handwritten drafts.
    - Zachem ia rodilsia v Rossii?, 1995 Dec. 29 (Box 15, Folder 29)
      Typescript, 2 p., 1995 Dec. 29; handwritten drafts, 7 p., n.d.
    - Zakonservirovannaia kultura, undated (Box 15, Folder 30)
      Typescript, 1 p., n.d.; handwritten drafts.
    - Zavalinka, undated (Box 15, Folder 31)
      Typescript, 1 p., n.d.; handwritten drafts, 4 p.
    - Zloradstvo, undated (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Zoia Osipova, undated (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Zvezda Gudiashvili, undated (Box 16, Folder 3)
      Handwritten drafts, 11 p. (one signed)
    - Collection of poems, 1971 (Box 16, Folder 4)
      Includes: Pesnia monakhov, Rechitativ Klaasa, Romans Filippa, Pesnia Nele, Pesnia Zhiliny, Pesnia Sleptsov, Pesnia Tilia, Pesnia Gezov. Typescript, 8 p., 1971.
    - Stikhi o Karelii: Vypiraiushenie valuny, Vozmutitel', Pozharnik v Kizhikh, Plakal'shchitsy, 1976 - 1988 (Box 16, Folder 5)
      Typescripts and handwritten drafts, ca. 1976 - 1988.
    - Dlia Tsedel'kovskogo: stikhi izbrannye avtorom [Poems chosen by the author], undated (Box 16, Folder 6)
      Copies of signed typescripts and typescripts with original signatures; handwritten list of poems [handwritten by Maria Yevtushenko?]
    - Miscellaneous groupings of poems, undated (Box 16, Folder 7)
      Includes: published pages of "Tom I: 1937 - 1958"; Materinstvo, Treugol'nik, Avtoportret, Liubopytstvo, Perspektiva; Posledniaia popytka (signed), Karlikovye berezy (signed), Plach po bratu (signed); Trinadtsat', Epilog; handwritten and typescript lists of poems.
    - Izbrannye proizvedennia v dvukh tomakh, 1975 (Box 16, Folder 8)
      Photocopy of p. 1-13 (4 pages per sheet of paper), 1975.
    - Yevgeny Yevtushenko: The Collected Poems: 1952 - 1990 (press release by Henry Holt and Company, Inc. and book cover) (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Literary Olympians 1992: An International Anthology (leaflet) (Box 16, Folder 10)
      Cover of leaflet includes a photograph of Yevtushenko.
    - Sobranie sochninenii v trekh tomakh (flyer) (Box 16, Folder 11)
      Printed on both sides.
    - "Early Poems" and "The Face Behind the Face" (Marion Boyars Publishers catalogs and flyer), undated (Box 16, Folder 12)
      3 catalogs; 1 flyer.
    - Yevg. Yevtushenko: 1949 - 1999: Vel XX: Stikhotvoreniia (galleys) (Box 16, Folder 13)
      67 p.; 1999.
    - The Best of the Best/ Luchshee iz luchshego (Galleys p. 1 - 74) (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - The Best of the Best/ Luchshee iz luchshego (Galleys p. 75 - end) (Box 16, Folder 15)
    - Pozdnie Slezy (transparency, p. 1 - 50) (Box 16, Folder 16)
    - Pozdnie Slezy (transparency, p. 51 - end) (Box 16, Folder 17)
    - Translation by Yevtushenko of poems by Gevorg Emin, undated (Box 16, Folder 18)
      Poems include: Zhaloba lorki, Grand Kan'on, Rech' Senatora Kolli, among others. Typescript, 6 p., n.d.
    - Translation by Yevtushenko of poems by William Jay Smith, undated (Box 16, Folder 19)
      Poems include: Slezy [Slezy Khrista?], Galileo Galilei, Amerikanskii primitiv. Typescript, 4 p.
    - Posle Stalina, 1962 (Box 16, Folder 20)
      Collection of poems published by Russian Language Specialties, 84 p., 1962.
    - Galleys for a multi-volume book of poetry [1 of 2] (Box 16, Folder 21)
    - Galleys for a multi-volume book of poetry [2 of 2] (Box 16, Folder 22)
    - 1995 - 1998 Drafts: Ballada o Mandel'shtame, 1998 Nov. (Box 16.1, Folder 1)
      Numerous typescripts and some handwritten drafts.
      Mandel'shtam, O.
    - 1995 - 1998 Drafts: The Conductor's Baton, to Kurt Masur, 1997 (Box 16.1, Folder 2)
      Annotated faxcopy in English (translated by Albert C. Todd), 2 p., 1997 Sept. 7; handwritten drafts, 3 p.
      Masur, Kurt; Todd, Albert
    - 1995 - 1998 Drafts: Ia rebenok liubvi, undated (Box 16.1, Folder 3)
      To Zhenia Yevtushenko the Younger, handwritten drafts, 2 p.
    - 1995 - 1998 Drafts: Light in August, undated (Box 16.1, Folder 4)
      Handwritten drafts in English, 2 p.
    - 1995 - 1998 Drafts: Menorah, 1997 (Box 16.1, Folder 5)
      Handwritten drafts in English, 2 p. Faxcopy of article from Associated Press in which Yevtushenko describes his writing of this poem, 1 p., 1997 Mar. 21.
    - 1995 - 1998 Drafts: New Year in Prague, 1997 (Box 16.1, Folder 6)
      Handwritten drafts in English, 10 p.
    - 1995 - 1998 Drafts: Shekspir o Mikhoelse (Box 16.1, Folder 7)
    - 1995 - 1998 Drafts: The Whisper of Ashes, undated (Box 16.1, Folder 8)
    - 1995 - 1998 Drafts: Untitled [1 of 2], undated (Box 16.1, Folder 9)
    - 1995 - 1998 Drafts: Untitled [2 of 2], undated (Box 16.1, Folder 10)
    - Drafts, 1999 (Box 16.1, Folder 11)
      Includes drafts of "Pamiati Georgiia Ivanova," "Za chto?" "Renessans," "Dva goria," "Odna minuto zla," "Kapkany," "Portret." Some poems are also dated 1957.
    - Miscellaneous poems [1 of 20], undated (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous poems [2 of 20], undated (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous poems [3 of 20], undated (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous poems [4 of 20], undated (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous poems [5 of 20], undated (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous poems [6 of 20], undated (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous poems [7 of 20], undated (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous poems [8 of 20], undated (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous poems [9 of 20], undated (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Miscellaneous poems [10 of 20], undated (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Miscellaneous poems [11 of 20], undated (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous poems [12 of 20], undated (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous poems [13 of 20], undated (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous poems [14 of 20], undated (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous poems [15 of 20], undated (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous poems [16 of 20], undated (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous poems [17 of 20], undated (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous poems [18 of 20], undated (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous poems [19 of 20], undated (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Miscellaneous poems [20 of 20], undated (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Poems and presentations in Chinese and Japanese [1 of 2], undated (Box 19, Folder 2)
      Photocopies of manuscripts in Chinese and Japanese.
    - Poems and presentations in Chinese and Japanese [2 of 2], undated (Box 19, Folder 3)
      Photocopies of manuscripts and typescripts in Chinese and Japanese.
    - Poems and presentations in Arabic, undated (Box 19, Folder 4)
      Photocopies, typescripts and manuscripts in Arabic.
    - Poems in German, undated (Box 19, Folder 5)
      Photocopies and typescripts. Poems include, among others: Gespräch, Solang auf Erden noch die Mörder gehn, Babij Jar, Die Mütter gehen leise von uns fort, Letzer Versuch, Russische Natur. Also includes (in English) a list of poems which should be included in the German edition of the 'Collected Poems.'
    - Poems in Hebrew, undated (Box 19, Folder 6)
      Typescripts, 4 p; faxcopy of typescript, 1 p., 1997 Mar. 16.
    - Stikhi Yevgeniia Yevtushenko v perevode na ivrit [List of Yevtushenko poems in Hebrew translation], undated (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Poems in Italian, undated (Box 19, Folder 8)
      Includes, among others: Dubi pri si mem necesas (1986); Amore, Dormi;Babij Jar; Le Betulle Nane; Due Citta; Gorbaciov in Oklahoma; Vorrei.
    - Poems in other languages: Miscellaneous, undated (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - English translation of "13", 1993 Oct. - 1996 May (Box 19, Folder 10)
      "The Thirteen"; translated by Albert C. Todd, typescript, 30 p., October 1993 - May 1996.
    - Poems in English: A - P, undated (Box 19, Folder 11)
      Includes: The Anthem without a Home (The Wandering Anthem); An Attempt at Blasphemy; Cemetary of Whales; The City of Yes, the City of No; Divorce; Do Russian People Stand for War?; Eyelashes; Firing Back...; The Final Shot; Flowers and Bullets; Hand-rolled Cigarettes; In Jail; Last Request; Legacy; Lies; Little Bells; Liudei neinteresnikh v mire net; Loss; Maternity Floor; Mayakovsky's Mother; The Mountain Road; The Face Behind the Face; The Soul; Verbosity; The Ringing of the Earth; But Before...; Polessa pola.
    - English: "Babii Iar", 1961 (Box 19, Folder 12)
      Babii Iar. Photocopy from book and leaflet (both translated by George Reavey); photocopy of translation by Archie Johnstone printed in "Literaturnaya Gazeta", 1961 Sep 19.
    - English: "I would like...", undated (Box 19, Folder 13)
    - Poems in English: R - Z, undated (Box 19, Folder 14)
      Includes: Procession with the Madonna; The Russian Blizzard; The School Master; Simbirsk Fair; The Tears of the Poor; Tenderness (translated by Lydia Slater); A Talk (translated by Lydia Slater); Excerpt from the poem "Under the Skin of the Statue of Liberty" (rough translation by Sam Sheiman); The Word; Who Are You, Grand Canyon? (translated by Albert C. Todd); You will love me... (translated by Albert C. Todd); 21st Century.
    - English: Russia's Tears, undated (Box 19, Folder 15)
      Also called "A Tear of Russia," typescript, 1 p. Handwritten drafts, 5 p., n.d.
    - Fragments of poems in English, undated (Box 19, Folder 16)
    - Collections of poems in English (Box 19, Folder 17)
      Includes: Japanese background, The Face Behind the Face. Last Attempt: Poetry and a Political Manifesto (by Yevgeny Yevtushenko, translated by Albert C. Todd), signed, 1988.
    - English: Miscellaneous, undated (Box 19, Folder 18)
      Includes a fax cover page to Alex Swenson from Jacqui Daniels; List of poems entitled From English Book "Collected Poems."
    - English: "The Dove in Santiago": translated by Jan Butler, 1972 - 1978 (Box 20, Folder 1)
      Annotated copy of typescript, 46 p., 1972 - 1978.
    - English: "Ivan the Terrible and Ivan the Fool": translated by Daniel Weissbort, 1979 (Box 20, Folder 2)
      Photocopy of book, 1979.
      Weissbort, Daniel
    - English: "Safari in Ulster": translated by Jan Butler and Michael Kustow, undated (Box 20, Folder 3)
      Photocopy, 4 p., n.d.
      Kustow, Michael; Butler, Jan
    - Greek translation: "Mama i neitronnaia bomba", 1985 (Box 20, Folder 4)
      Photocopy, 60 p., 1985.
    - Poems in Portuguese, undated (Box 20, Folder 5)
      Includes: A Chave Do Comandante; Amor À Portuguesa; As Fronteiras; Babii Yar; Dorme, Amor; Entre a Cidade sim e a Cidade Não; Fátima; Feira em Simbirsk; Granizo Sobre Khárkov; Imagem de Infância; Impressões do Cinema Ocidental; Monólogo Duma Actriz; Quirera ter Nascido em Todos os Paises.
    - Spanish: Poems A - D, undated (Box 20, Folder 6)
      Includes: Los abedules enanos; La abuela; El ajedrez de Mexico; A la memoria de Jose Maria Arguedas; Bodas; El cementerio de las ballenas; A Chuquicamata; Las botas de los generales; Colon con las uñas sucias (Fucu); Conversación; Duerme, amor...
    - Spanish: Babiy Yar, undated (Box 20, Folder 7)
      Typescripts and photocopies from books, n.d.
    - Spanish: Corrida, undated (Box 20, Folder 8)
      Typescripts, n.d.
    - Spanish: Poems E - Z, undated (Box 20, Folder 9)
      Includes: La ejecucion de Stenka Razin; Entre la ciudad Sí y la ciudad No; La feria de Simbirsk; Granizo in Járkov; La llave del comandante; Mensaje a Pablo Neruda; La miel; La mitad no quiero de nada!; Monolog; Una procesió de la Virgen; Sonrisas; Tres minutos de verdad; Ya no te quiero mas.
    - Spanish: La Paloma en Santiago, undated (Box 20, Folder 10)
      Photocopies and typescripts.
    - Spanish: Mi Peruana [or "Peruana Mia'], undated (Box 20, Folder 11)
    - Spanish: Yo quisiera..., undated (Box 20, Folder 12)
    - Spanish: Fragments of poems, undated (Box 20, Folder 13)
    - Spanish: Miscellaneous, undated (Box 20, Folder 14)
    - Spanish: Collections of poems, undated (Box 20, Folder 15)
      Includes: El viento de mañana; Agente de seguros; La sonrisa osada; Auriculares para tomates; Los genes; Hace tanto; Las botas; (a Bela Ajmadúlina); La tercera nieve; Exorcisno; Granizo en Járkov.
    - "Collected works", undated (Box 87, Folder 1)
      Correspondence.
    - "Collected works", undated (Box 87, Folder 2)
      Signed typescript of poems and lists of poems.
    - "Fenechka", 2000 Apr. 25 (Box 87, Folder 3)
      Signed typescript, fragments with handwritten notes.
    - "Fuku", 1985 (Box 87, Folder 4)
      Off-print from "Novyi Mir".
    - "Kak ne khvataet Sakharova nam", undated (Box 87, Folder 5)
      Signed typescript, 1p., n. d.; handwritten drafts, 3 p., n. d.
    - "Monolog Shekspira", undated (Box 87, Folder 6)
      Photocopy of signed handwritten draft, 5p., n. d.
    - "Prizhok", undated (Box 87, Folder 7)
      Handwritten draft, 10 p., n. d.
    - "Semi-emigration", undated (Box 87, Folder 8)
      Signed typescript, 2 p., n. d.
    - "Sovetskye emigranti', undated (Box 87, Folder 9)
      Typescript, 1 p., n. d.
    - "The untied shoelaces", 2000 Apr. 16 (Box 87, Folder 10)